A Finding Aid to the Robert Sperry Papers, 1951-2002, in the Archives of American Art AAA.sperrobe
Archives of American Art
Robert Sperry papers
1951-2002
AAA.sperrobe
Archives of American Art
11 Linear feet
The papers of ceramicist Robert Sperry measure 11 linear feet and date from 1951-2002. The collection documents Sperry's career as an artist, teacher, and filmmaker through biographical information, correspondence, exhibition files, gallery files, material on projects and workshops, writings, a scrapbook, financial files, printed material, photographs, VHS and reel-to-reel motion picture films, and artwork.
Sperry, Robert, 1927-1998
Biographical Note
Robert Sperry was born in Bushnell, Illinois, in 1927. He grew up on his family's farm in Druid, Saskatchewan, Canada, and in 1945 was drafted into the U.S. Army, where he first developed an interest in art. After serving in the military, he returned home and completed his B.A. at the University of Saskatchewan in 1950 and a B.F.A. at the Art Institute of Chicago in 1953. While working on his B.A. he met and married Edyth MacDonald and they had one child, Van, in 1950. He spent one summer as Artist in Residence at the Archie Bray Foundation, in Helena, Montana, and then moved his family to Seattle so that he could complete his M.F.A. at the University of Washington. After graduating in 1955 he stayed at the University and became a professor, teaching ceramics until retiring in 1982. During this time, Sperry widely exhibited his clay vessels in both group and solo exhibitions and was active in the American Craft Council.
When not teaching, Robert Sperry pursued his interest in photography and filmmaking and, in 1963, traveled to Japan to make "Village Potters of Onda," a project that included a documentary film and a collection of black and white photographs. Sperry continued experimenting with film and, in 1967, created a fictional film entitled, "Profiles Cast Long Shadows," which was shown at film festivals throughout the United States. After abandoning another film project in 1970 while going through a divorce, he returned to ceramics as his focus. During the 1970s Sperry developed his techniques, modifying glazes and moving away from the vessel shape. In 1976 Sperry married Patti Warashina, fellow ceramicist and professor at the University of Washington. He began producing murals, which led to several public commissions such as a mural for the IBM Field Engineering Educational Center in Atlanta, created in 1983. Robert Sperry: A Retrospective, was exhibited in 1985-1986 at the Bellevue Art Museum, however, Sperry would continue producing and exhibiting new work, and giving lectures and workshops for thirteen more years, until his death in 1998.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of ceramicist Robert Sperry measure 11 linear feet and date from 1951-2002. The collection documents Sperry's career as an artist and teacher through biographical information, correspondence, exhibition files, gallery files, material on projects and workshops, writings, a scrapbook, financial files, printed material, photographs, films, and artwork.
Biographical files contain items outlining Sperry's career including resumes, teaching evaluations, awards, and interviews. Correspondence includes general correspondence with family, friends, colleagues, schools, galleries, art organizations, and publications as well as named files for those with whom Sperry exchanged a significant amount of correspondence over a long period of time. The Exhibition Files contain materials on group and solo exhibitions Robert Sperry participated in, while Gallery Files hold material, such as correspondence and contracts, related to the galleries which exhibited Sperry's work primarily after 1979. The Project and Workshop Files in Series 5 contain material related to public commissions he completed and workshops he gave during the 1980s and 1990s.
Writings encompass writings by Sperry and others. Sperry's writings vary greatly and include drafts of articles, a family history, poetry, notes and a screenplay, while writings by others are primarily essays on art. Within this series Sperry's event calendars are also found. Sperry compiled a scrapbook which spans 1955 to 1964 and includes correspondence and printed material about exhibitions and newspaper clippings which feature his artwork. He and his wife, Patti Warashina, also compiled Financial Records primarily of their business and living expenses from 1976 to 1984 and earnings as artists and professors at the University of Washington.
The largest series in this collection, Printed Material, provides information largely on Sperry's career through press clippings, exhibition announcements, catalogs, and publications, and also includes other materials on ceramics in general. The Photographs series contains both photos and negatives from Sperry's trip to Japan to film "Village Potters of Onda" as well as photographs of his artwork and his family. Also found in this collection are a few sketches and drawings by Sperry and one drawing by Patti Warashina. Motion Picture Films consist of both VHS, which includes two documentaries on Sperry, and numerous reel-to-reel films which include footage for Sperry's films "Village Potters of Onda" and "Profiles Cast Long Shadows" as well as other experimental studies.
Arrangement
The Robert Sperry papers are arranged as thirteen series, according to type of material. Each series is arranged either in rough chronological or alphabetical order.
Series 1: Biographical Files, 1954-circa 2000, undated (Box 1; 0.3 linear feet)
Series 2: Correspondence Files, 1951-2000, undated (Boxes 1-2; 0.9 linear feet)
Series 3: Exhibition Files, 1963-1999, undated (Boxes 2-3; 1.2 linear feet)
Series 4: Gallery Files, 1960-2000, undated (Boxes 3-4; 0.8 linear feet)
Series 5: Project and Workshop Files, 1967-1996, undated (Box 4; 0.4 linear feet)
Series 6: Writings, 1966-1990, undated (Box 5; 0.5 linear feet)
Series 7: Scrapbook, 1955-1964 (Box 5; 8 folders)
Series 8: Financial Records, 1961-1995, undated (Boxes 5-6; 1.0 linear feet)
Series 9: Miscellaneous Subject Files, 1975-1998, undated (Box 6; 0.2 linear feet)
Series 10: Printed Material, 1955-2002, undated (Boxes 6-10; 3.4 linear feet)
Series 11: Photographs, 1963, undated (Box 10; 0.2 linear feet)
Series 12: Sketches and Drawings, 1984, undated (Box 10; 2 folders)
Series 13: Motion Picture Films, circa 1963-1998, undated (Boxes 10-11; 1.5 linear feet)
Related Material
Also found in the Archives of American Art are the Patti Warashina papers, circa 1900-1991. An online finding aid is available.
Provenance
The Robert Sperry papers were donated by Sperry's wife Patti Warashina in 2003 and 2004.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research. Use requires an appointment.
Nanette L. Laitman Documentation Project for Craft and Decorative Arts in America; University of Washington. -- Faculty; Warashina, Patti, 1940-; Ceramicists--Washington (State); Ceramics--Study and teaching; Drawings; Filmmakers; Interviews; Motion pictures (visual works); Photographs; Potters--Japan; Scrapbooks; Sketches; Transcripts; Videotapes; Works of art
- Biographical Files, 1954-circa 2000, undated; Series 1; (Box 1; 0.3 linear feet)
  Scope and Contents note
  This series includes artist statements, curriculum vitae and resumes, as well as a complete biography listing all of Sperry's professional achievements. It also contains files on awards Robert Sperry received which typically include correspondence, brochures, and other related materials concerning the awards. There are two files on interviews, including a transcript for an interview conducted by the Archives of American Art for the Northwest Oral History Project and two audio cassettes of a radio interview. Also found are teaching evaluations, Patti Warashina's resume, and other miscellaneous materials. The series is arranged alphabetically by type of material, with miscellaneous materials at the end.
  - Artist Statements, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Award, Bellevue Film Festival, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Award, International Academy of Ceramics Membership, 1983-1986, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Award, National Endowment for the Arts Visual Artists Fellowship Grant, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Award, American Crafts Council Honorary Fellow, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Biography, circa 2000 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Curriculum Vitae and Bibliography, 1956-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Interview, Audio Cassette, "Private Talks with Public Artists,", 1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Interview, Transcript, Archives of American Art, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Memorial Announcement, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Patti Warashina Short Resume, circa 1998 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Selected Resumes, 1954, 1991-1999 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Teaching Evaluations, 1957-1961 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Who's Who in American Art,", undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous, 1954-1988, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Correspondence Files, 1951-2000, undated; Series 2; (Boxes 1-2; 0.9 linear feet)
  This series contains both personal and professional correspondence. However, some correspondence related to Robert Sperry's professional career is also located within series 3, 4, and 5.
  Arrangement note
  The Correspondence Files are organized into two subseries:
  2.1: General Correspondence, 1951-2000, undated
  2.2: Named Files, 1955-1999, undated
  - General Correspondence, 1951-2000, undated; 2.1
    General Correspondence primarily consists of letters from family, friends, artists, and colleagues, including numerous cards and postcards. Also within are professional correspondence from galleries, schools, art associations, and art publications. An item of note is a letter to Sperry from artist Morris Graves, written June 14, 1967. Files are arranged chronologically by year.
    - General Correspondence, 1951-2000, undated (Box 1, Folder 16-37)
  - Named Files, 1955-1999, undated; 2.2
    Named Files are arranged alphabetically by the correspondent's name and contain letters, cards and postcards to Sperry. Included are files on individuals, primarily family, friends, and colleagues, with whom Sperry exchanged a significant amount of correspondence over a long period of time. Also found are files on museums, schools, art organizations, and publications. Most notable are several handmade birthday and anniversary cards given to Sperry by his wife, Patti Warashina.
    - A. Kaup & Associates, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Alfred Auerbach Associates, 1962, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - American Craft Council, 1959-1975, 1993-1997 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Art in Form, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Art Resource Technology, 1986, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Baross Films, 1979, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Bauer, Fred, 1964, 1991, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Bauer, Gretchen, 1983, 1987, undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Bauer, Lisa, 1984-1990 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Beigler, Myron (Mike) and Dolly, 1987, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Biskeborn, Susan, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Caruso, Nino, 1965-1966, 1975-1992, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Ceramics: Art and Perception, 1991, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Ceramics Monthly, 1976-1986 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Cleveland Museum of Art, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Chasanoff, Allan, 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Dobson, Dwight and Nancy, 1986-1996 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Earnest, Aileen Ryan, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Efron, Jean, 1988-1993, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Everson Museum of Art, 1962-1965, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Fisher, Robert, 1992-1993, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Gibson, Marge and Bob, 1984, 1993, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Griffith, Malcolm, 1986-1989, 1998, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Guggenheim, Shelly and Judy Mannes, 1985-1989, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Harlow, Margaret, 1993, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Harrington, LaMar, 1979-1984, 1994, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Harry N. Abrams, Inc., 1979, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Jacobs, Daniel, 1981-1982, 1987-1991 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Kehl, Richey, 1973, 1998, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Kleinsmith, Gene, 1984-1987 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Kolva, Jim, and Pat Sullivan, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Kurath, Martha S. (Jody), 1981, 1987-1997, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Larsen, Jack, 1982, 1990-1993, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Mahler Fine Arts Consulting, Inc., 1999 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Mannheimer, Joan, 1981-1987 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Marquis, Pamela, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Metapsychology, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - McDowell, Scott, 1977, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Museum of Contemporary Crafts, 1962, 1964-1966, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Nelson, Glenn C., 1964, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Newton, Dorothy (Dot), 1984-1997, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Nordness, Lee, 1977, 1988-1994 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Oregon Ceramic Studio, 1961-1965 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Peterson, Susan, 1980-1997 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Poole, Kristin M., 1991 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - PONCHO, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Publicity Letters, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Recommendation Letters for Students, 1973-1994, undated (Box 2, Folder 39-40)
    - Schwartz, Judith, 1981-1985, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Seattle Art Museum, 1974-1991, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Seattle Arts Commission, 1981-1986 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Sinker, John, Jr., 1993, undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Smith, Paul J., 1987, 1990, undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Smithsonian Institution, 1962-1964, undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Sperry, Kathy and Chris Walton, 1990-1993, undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Sperry, Van and Family, 1986, 1990, 1996, undated (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Staggs, Virginia (Jinks), 1984, 1990-1996, undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - St. Martin's College, Olympia, Washington, 1960-1962 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - University of British Columbia, 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - University of Washington, 1955-1989 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - U.S. Department of State, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Warashina, Patti, 1976-1997, undated (Box 2, Folder 54-55)
    - Wilson, Ian and Bette, 1981-1997, undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Wing Luke Memorial Museum, 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Zakin, Richard, 1982-1993, undated (Box 2, Folder 58)
- Exhibition Files, 1963-1999, undated; Series 3; (Boxes 2-3; 1.2 linear feet)
  Exhibition Files contain material on the group and solo exhibitions in which Robert Sperry participated. Files typically include correspondence, expense lists and receipts, notes, and printed materials, including brochures, announcements, and press clippings. Most notable is the material on Robert Sperry: A Retrospective, held in 1985 at the Bellevue Art Museum. Files are arranged chronologically by year of exhibition.
  - The Village Potters of Onda (1964-1966), 1963-1966, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - American Studio Pottery (1966), 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Burien Art Festival (1966) (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - "Form and Quality" (1966, 1967), 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Distinguished Contemporary Potters Invitational Show (1975) (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Functional Ceramics (1977) (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Robert Sperry at Nagatani Gallery, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Function: Non-Function (1979) (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Robert Sperry at Erica Williams/Anne Johnson Gallery (1979-1980), 1979, undated (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Crafts Northwest Circa 1980, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Contemporary Ceramics: Response to Wedgewood (1980) (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - American Crats (1980), 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Ceramic Sculpture Invitational at Whatcom Museum of History & Art (1980) (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - The Washington Year: A Contemporary View (1981), 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Wichita Art Association Decorative Arts Retrospective (1981), 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - "Ceramic Traditions" (1981-1983) (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Robert Sperry at Erica Williams/Anne Johnson Gallery (1981), 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - "American Clay II" (1982) (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Pacific Currents/Ceramics 1982 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Variations in Clay (1982) (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Robert Sperry at Gordon Woodside/John Braseth Galleries (1983) (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Potter's Choice (1983), 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - "Regional Crafts: A Contemporary Perspective" (1983-1984) (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Clay: 1984, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Platters and Related Forms (1984) (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Ceramic Sculpture Invitational (1984), 1984, undated (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Skeet Shoot (1984) (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Potters & Prints (1984-1985) (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Robert Sperry: A Retrospective (1985-1986), 1983-1986 (Box 2, Folder 87-89)
  - 10/40 Anniversary Celebration at the Bellevue Art Museum (1986), 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Pacific Northwest Art Expo (1986) (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Northwest Impressions: Works on Paper (1986) (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - West Coast Clay (1986) (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Outside Japan (1986), 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - Drawn to the Surface: Artists in Clay and Glass (1987) (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - "Now & Then" (1987) (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Robert Sperry: Ceramics, Paperworks, Drawings (1987), 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - FOCUS: Seattle (1987), 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Ceramics in Architecture: Drawings, Sketches, and Models" (1987), 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Canton Art Institute Ceramic Invitational (1987), 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Northwest Clay (1987), 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Marylhurst College, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Craft Today: Poetry of the Physical (1987-1988), 1985-1988 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Clay Revisions: Plate, Cup, Vase (1987-1989), 1986-1989 (Box 3, Folder 7-8)
  - "A Fine Place to Work: The Legacy of the Archie Bray Foundation" (1988) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Black and White (1988) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Architectural Art: Affirming the Design Relationship (1988), 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Robert Sperry at Whatcom Museum of History & Art (1988), 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - "School of Art: Students and Teachers at the University of Washington, 1975-1988" (1988) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Contemporary Survey: A Visible Presence in the Northwest (1988), 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Northwest Ceramics, Today (1988-1989), 1986-1989 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Washington Crafts: Then & Now (1989), 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Northwest Designer Craftsmen, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - "Mirror Images: Reflections in Clay" (1989) (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Surface and Form (1989) (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - The Spectacle of Chaos (1989) (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Bumbershoot: Decade of Abstraction 1979-1989 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Media Gallery (1989), 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Clay AZ Art XV (1989), 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Clay Now (1989), 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Michigan Ceramics '89, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Art Works for AIDS (1990), 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - 100 Years of Washington Art: New Perspectives (1990) (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Robert Sperry at Janet Hudson Gallery (1990) (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Black & White: An Exhibition of Contemporary Ceramics (1990), 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - "13th Annual Clay Exhibition" at Millersville University (1990), 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - NCECA Conference 1991, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - "Beyond Serving" (1991), 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Minor Works by Major Artists (1991), 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Artists at Work (1991), 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Archie Bray Foundation Benefit Exhibition (1991) (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Robert Sperry at Helen Drutt Gallery (1991) (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Swidler Gallery (1991) (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - The Artful Charger (1991), 1989-1991 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Walls: Large-Scale Ceramic Sculpture Eight Variations (1991), 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Masterworks: Pacific Northwest Arts and Crafts Now (1991) (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Seattle Art Tour (1992) (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Black & White Ceramics II (1992), 1990-1992 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Corporate Art West (1992) (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - National Ceramic Invitational (1992), 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Twist Platter Exhibition (1992) (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Revolving Techniques (1992), 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - 1992 Ceramics Invitational at Sunbird Gallery, 1991-1993 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - "Studio Potter's Twentieth Anniversary Collection" (1992), 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Schneider-Bluhm-Loeb Gallery Show, 1992-1993, undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Robert Sperry at the National Academy of Sciences (1993), 1991-1994 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Pacific Rim Japan (1993) (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Green Meadow Invitational Pottery Show (1993), 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - North by Northwest (1993) (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Artfair Seattle 1993 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Year of the American Craft (1993), 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - "Clay 1993: A National Survey," (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Contemporary American Ceramics (1993), 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Robert Sperry: New Works (1993), 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Chicago International New Art Forms Exposition (1993) (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Architectural Clay (1993), 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Living Treasures (1993), 1992-1993, undated (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - The Legacy of the Archie Bray Foundation (1993) (Box 3, Folder 62-63)
  - Art Works for AIDS '93, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - "Arts and Crafts of the Pacific Northwest" (1994) (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - "30 Ceramic Sculptors Exhibition" (1994) (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - James Renwick Alliance Tour to Seattle (1994) (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Contemporary Crafts and the Saxe Collection (1994), 1991-1994 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Potters & Prints (1994) (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - "Influence and Introspection: Pacific NW Ceramics" (1995) (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - "Heart of the Arts" (1995), 1994 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Art Works for AIDS (1995), 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - "Clay: a Continuing Tradition" (1996) (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - The Estate of Robert Sperry: Ceramics and Prints (1999) (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Miscellaneous, 1964-1966, 1975-1999, undated (Box 3, Folder 75-79)
- Gallery Files, 1962-2000, undated; Series 4; (Boxes 3-4; 0.8 linear feet)
  This series contains files for galleries which exhibited and sold works by Robert Sperry, and may include exhibition announcements and invitations, brochures, correspondence with Sperry, contracts, invoices, and consignment lists and agreements. However, materials relating to certain exhibitions will be found in the Exhibition files in Series 3. The bulk of the material is dated after 1979 with the exception of the Henry Gallery, America House, and the Contemporary Crafts Gallery. Materials in this series are arranged alphabetically by gallery name.
  - Albertson-Peterson Gallery, Inc., 1984-1993, undated (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - America House, 1960-1966, undated (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - American Craft Museum, 1981-1997, undated (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Annex Gallery, 1987, undated (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Art South, 1986, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Bellevue Art Museum, 1979-1986, 1991, 1998, undated (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Bentley-Tomlinson Gallery, 1992-1995, undated (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Contemporary Crafts Gallery, 1967, 1975-1986, undated (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Cross Creek Gallery, 1986-1987, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Dorothy Weiss Gallery, 1985-2000 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Elaine Potter Gallery, 1984-1986, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Elements Gallery/Eddy Beasley Associates, 1982-1992, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Erica Williams/Anne Johnson Gallery, 1979-1982, 1992, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)